(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, welcome
back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're at a wedding ceremony.
- All right, nice.
- Another nice wedding.
- Yeah.
- But of course, it wouldn't be English Pod
unless we have something
unexpected happening at this wedding.
Okay, so we're gonna
be talking about hands.
- Oh, but Marco, what is
there to say about hands?
- Well, as you may or may not know,
each finger has a name on your hand.
- Okay. - So we're gonna learn how,
so we're gonna learn what
those names are in English.
- Perfect.
And also we're gonna
learn about some common
phrases that you might
hear in an English wedding.
- Exactly, because I think, exactly
because usually it's old English.
Maybe English that's not used anymore.
- All right, well, I'm excited to find
out what this unexpected event is.
So let's listen to our
dialogue for the first time.
(upbeat music)
(light music)
- The rings, please.
May this ring be blessed, so he
who gives it and she who wears it
may abide in peace and continue in love
until lives and with this ring, I be wed.
Where it is a symbol of
our love and commitment.
- Honey, that's my pinky.
That ring goes on the ring finger.
- So what?
- That's my index finger.
- No, right, this one, right?
That's the thumb make.
Okay, I got it.
This is the ring finger.
- That's my middle finger, Nick.
This is my ring finger.
(audience laughing)
(upbeat music)
- All right, embarrassing
moment for the groom.
- Yes.
- Confusing the fingers in
front of all his friends and family.
Not good.
So I mentioned before that
we're gonna learn the names
of each finger in your hand.
So let's get started.
Let's take a look at these
in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- All right, well why don't we start
with the smallest finger on your hand?
- The smallest finger on your hand.
That's called the pinky pinky pinky.
- Sometimes people
call it the little finger.
- Yes.
- Right?
- Yep.
- So the pinky and the next finger
is the one the groom couldn't find.
- Okay, the ring finger.
- The ring finger.
- So this is of course like the name says,
where the wedding ring is usually placed.
- Exactly.
- It's a finger.
- Now the next one is
a controversial finger.
- That must be the middle finger.
- Okay, easy, middle finger.
So why is it controversial?
- Well, you know, if you put your
middle finger up and you put all the--
- I'll be doing right now to me.
I'm sorry Marco, I'll do it this way.
And all other fingers down.
You are making a very rude gesture.
- It's a rude sign.
- So what would you call that?
- I would call that
giving the middle finger.
- Giving the middle finger.
Or I've also heard the
phrase flip someone off.
- Yes.
Or also flip the bird.
- Flip the bird, exactly.
Or give him the bird.
- Yes.
So all phrases that you
can use when you are
showing only your
middle finger to somebody.
- It's not very polite.
- No, don't do it.
- Don't do it.
Unless somebody deserves it, I guess.
- Well, we won't talk about that.
But what we will talk
about is the next finger.
- The index finger.
- The index finger. - Index finger.
- So this is the finger you use to point.
- Right.
- Yeah.
- The index finger.
Any idea why they call it the index finger?
- 'Cause when you're looking through the
index of a book, you always use this finger.
- Right, I think you also use this
finger to pass pages on a book, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay, don't believe
anything I just told you.
- Well, we're not sure.
Maybe you guys know
the real answer to this.
- All right.
- And our last finger, the
most important one, the thumb.
- The thumb.
- T-H-U-M-B.
- Thumb.
- Okay, so that's the short but fat finger.
- The very moveable one.
- The moveable one.
- The one that you use to place station in.
- Video games.
- Okay, so the pronunciation here.
Do you say the B at the end of this word?
- No, I will actually only pronounce the M.
- Yes.
- The thumb.
- Yeah, you wouldn't say the thumb.
- No.
- Okay, so now that we're
clear on all five fingers,
let's listen to our dialogue
again, and then we'll come back
and talk about these difficult
phrases that the priest use.
(upbeat music)
The rings, please.
May this ring be blessed, so he
who gives it, and she who wears
it may abide in peace and
continue in love until lives end.
- With this ring, I thee wed.
- Wear it as a symbol of
our love and commitment.
- Honey, that's my pinky.
The ring goes on the ring finger.
- This one?
- That's my index finger.
- No, right.
This one, right?
That's the thumb, Nick.
Okay, I got it.
This is the ring finger.
- That's my middle finger, Nick.
This is my ring finger.
- Oh.
(upbeat music)
- Well, this is really common
wedding speak, isn't it?
- Yeah, it's really common.
That's what usually the priest or the
person who is marrying somebody would say.
- Well, why don't we look
at some of these phrases now
because it's really interesting
to talk about their meaning.
So the first one, may this ring be blessed?
- May this ring be blessed.
So what does it mean when
you bless something or someone?
- Well, usually the religious
leader does this, right?
And he's giving good wishes to that thing.
- Could be for an object
or to a person, right?
- Yes. - You can be blessed as well.
And so these good wishes
usually come from God.
- Okay, great.
So what about our next phrase?
- A bide in peace.
- Wow, so this verb a bide.
- It means to live, to
live, to be, to be in peace.
But it's very fancy.
And I don't know if you use it anymore.
- No, I think you would never
use this word in conversation
or even very rarely in
writing, it's quite old.
- Yes, definitely I would agree.
So a bide in peace.
Okay, what about our next phrase?
I like this and it's the
common phrase you'll
hear in all movies
and in all marriages.
- Yeah, with this ring, I, the wed.
- With this ring, I, the wed.
- Okay, we've got two words in
here that are also older English words.
So the, the, T-H-E-E.
T-H-E-E.
The.
So this is a middle English term for you.
- You, right.
- So I would, can I say I love the?
- You could, that would be very romantic.
- Yeah.
- Also inappropriate for the office.
But it's very old, I guess
you would, if you're reading
Shakespeare, you would
definitely come upon this, right?
- Yes, yes.
- And what about wed?
- This is also an old word for an old
verb for the action of marrying someone.
- So I can say, we will be wed next year.
But don't say that now
because you'll sound quite silly.
- Yeah.
- It's two old fashions.
- Yeah, I guess so.
But it's good to know,
especially if you guys are
reading something a
little bit more classical.
- Or you plan to get
married to an English person.
(laughing)
- All right, and our last phrase, wear it
as a symbol of our love and commitment.
- Wear it as a symbol of
our love and commitment.
- So now he's referring
to the rings, right?
- Yeah. - Where the ring has a symbol.
- A sign.
- A representation.
- Yes.
- Of love and commitment.
So why would you wear a
ring as a symbol of something?
- Well, obviously, you know, love.
You can't see it, you can't touch it.
- Right?
- So you need something
to show you that it's there.
So you need a sign of that love.
- Something that you can see.
So that's what the ring represents.
- Yeah.
- But how about this word, commitment?
- The commitment is a strong promise.
So you promise to love that
person to take care of them.
- Yes, it is.
- Yeah, okay, great.
So now we are a little bit more familiar
with some of the language
you hear in a wedding ceremony.
And we also know all of
the names of the fingers.
- Exactly.
- So why don't we listen to the dialogue
one more time to hear these all in context?
(upbeat music)
- The ring is pleased.
May this ring be blessed.
So he who gives it, and
she who wears it may abide
in peace and continue
in love until life's end.
With this ring, I thee wed,
where it is a symbol of
our love and commitment.
- Honey, that's my pinky.
That ring goes on the ring finger.
- So what?
- That's my index finger.
- No, right.
This one, right?
That's the time make.
Okay, I got it.
- This is the ring finger.
- That's my middle finger, Nick.
This is my ring finger.
(audience laughing)
(upbeat music)
- All right, so now it's perfectly clear
and a romantic dialogue in the end.
- Yeah, very romantic.
- Although a little bit embarrassing.
- Yeah.
- So what about wedding rings?
Now we have different
types of rings, right?
We have the wedding ring,
the one that we just heard.
- Yeah.
- But we also have an engagement ring.
- Yes, yeah.
In most English speaking
countries, the woman
is very, very lucky
because she gets two rings.
- Right.
- So when the man asks her to
marry him, he gives her a diamond.
- A diamond ring.
That is usually, that's
the engagement ring.
And it's really, really
important that he does this.
(laughs)
And it's also really important
that he spends a lot of money
on the end of the diamonds.
- Yeah, I know about this.
- The diamonds are forever, right?
- Yes, and the tradition is you
must spend at least one month salary.
- Wow, I said it.
- Yeah.
- So the girl gets a
diamond engagement ring
and then on wedding day,
she gets the wedding ring.
- Yes.
- And usually, will she wear both of them?
- Yeah, she'll always wear both of them.
So the engagement ring goes closest
to you and then the wedding ring on top.
- And the engagement ring, it
represents the commitment to marry her.
- So wait, the commitment
from the man to marry her.
- Okay, so that it's a symbol
that they will get married.
- Yes, it's a symbol of the promise.
- Now what happens if they break
up and they don't get married?
Does he get the ring back?
- I don't know.
- Okay, here's the rule.
If he was a jerk, no, but if it
was sort of like a happy break up,
then okay.
- Okay, I guess it's a big risk, right?
(laughs)
- All right, so that's all for today, guys.
Let us know if you guys have
any interesting wedding stories.
I know that sometimes weddings
can be embarrassing people,
I don't know, objecting,
maybe I've seen the groom
faint or even fall in
a pool, fall in a pool.
So if you have any stories,
please share them with us.
Come to EnglishPod.
com and also if you have
any questions or doubts,
Eric and I are always
there to answer them.
- Well, thanks for listening to this lesson
everyone and until next time, goodbye.
(upbeat music)